This video is sponsored by the
all-in-one website builder and business
management software, ODU. Use my link in
the description to get started for free.
Tyler had just moved away from his
childhood hometown. It was his first job
working for a big company in a big city,
the next expected [music] step. On one
of his first days in the office, a
co-orker named Daniel sat next to him at
one of the large desks [music] toward
the side of the open floor plan. The two
introduced each other and Tyler told him
he was new to the city and [music] that
it was his first time living anywhere
outside his hometown as well as on his
own. Well, congrats and welcome. Big
steps, Daniel said genuinely. Word of
advice, the best way to get familiar
with the city and plug into everything
is to go out as much as you can. Don't
hide inside. The night life here is
really the best way to do that. Just say
yes to everything. Bars, clubs, shows,
events.
Okay. Yeah, that makes sense, Tyler
said. Actually, you know what? You
should come out with me and a couple of
friends this weekend. Okay, sure.
That Friday, Tyler met up with Daniel
and a few of Daniel's friends at a bar
named Fool's Gold. They drank a bit,
then they went to several other bars and
clubs and did the same. The next
afternoon, Daniel texted Tyler and
invited him out again. Tyler accepted
and the night went about the same as the
[music] one prior. The following
weekends and soon during the weeks as
well, Tyler continued to go out to bars,
clubs, and show venues. Sometimes with
Daniel, sometimes with other people he
had since met. At any given time
throughout the week, Tyler was either
completely buzzing or completely numb.
He looked different. He had gained a
noticeable amount of weight. His quality
of work had also lagged. So much so that
at his first performance review, one of
his managers, Katie, shared that there
was some slack he needed to tighten up.
I understand it could be a big change
and acclimating to a new environment and
new company culture can take time. I
find that it can really help to have
strong anchors of discipline. Katie
said, "Yeah, no, that makes sense."
Tyler agreed. You know, we have a
running group that many of us
participate in. We go every morning. You
should come. Could be a great way to
inspire a bit more structure in your
life. Two mornings later, Tyler met at
the running club's gathering spot. He
noticed another co-orker from the same
department he worked in, Andre. Not
knowing anyone else other than his
manager. Tyler quickly buddied up with
Andre. They introduced each other more
formally and Tyler told Andre that he
was relatively new to the city. He told
him he had been doing a lot of the
nightlife stuff. His tone almost making
it sound like it was obligatory. Yeah,
man. I get doing all that. It can be
real tempting in a city like this, but
that will eat you up. Best way to
sustain here, honestly, is to tap into
the fitness scene. It helps keep you in
check and always active. Depression
can't hit a moving target, right? Yeah,
true. That makes sense, Tyler responded.
In the coming weeks, then months, Tyler
found himself going to the running club
nearly every day. He also joined Andre
in training for an upcoming marathon,
often running both before and after
work. He began going to bed early every
night and waking up [music] early every
morning. He stopped going to bars and
clubs and late night shows and events.
He filled a schedule with the gym, cold
plunges, saunas, red light therapy, and
fitness group events and meetups.
Several new acquaintances also clued him
into various [music] apps and trackers
and data he could use in reference to
help optimize his habits and schedule.
His life was in perfect order. His
decisions required less and less of him.
Tyler had lost a noticeable amount of
weight. He looked different. His work
performance had improved. As that became
more apparent to management, [music] he
was added to a team focused on new
growth related projects. A solid
opportunity for a potential [music]
promotion. the expected next step. The
team was led by an individual named
Alex, a bald, slender, and extremely
well-dressed man. A few weeks into
working with Alex, Tyler had become
somewhat friends with him, at least on a
co-orker level. One afternoon, after a
meeting, Tyler asked him if he wanted to
join him at the running club the next
morning. I appreciate the offer, but
I'll have to pass. I'll be working at
6:30, Tyler asked, confused. Yeah, have
a lot to do and honestly I'm a bit of a
hermit. I try to stay away from the
pulse of the city and closer to my own
if that makes sense. I mostly just go to
work, gym, home, repeat. Pretty boring.
My goal is upper management by 30s.
Seauite eventually, a wife and a quiet
family life, so I'm trying to be laser
focused right now. Monk mode, I think,
is what they call it. Right. No, that
makes sense. [music] Tyler agreed. As
Tyler began to spend more time working
with Alex, he also began to go into the
office earlier and leave later. He ran
less, stopped doing many of the health
rituals he had picked up, stopped
attending many of the fitness group
events, stopped going out much
altogether. He focused increasingly on
time by himself, his career, and his
money. Soon, he found his environment
and lifestyle whittleled down to little
more than that. Naturally, this made it
much harder to meet people, particularly
women. And so Tyler began using various
dating apps. After a lot of back and
forth messaging amounting to nothing,
and several dates that were duds, he met
a woman named Anne. They seemed to hit
it off. She was an artist, also somewhat
new to the city. She loved going out and
exploring the area, checking out the art
and music scenes, [music]
the parks and festivals and fairs. She
loved day adventures and aesthetic
[music] experiences. On paper, she
appeared to be nothing like Tyler, and
yet they seem to work together
frictionlessly.
One night, a few weeks into casually
dating, the two sat [music] in Tyler's
apartment, scrolling through movies and
shows on various streaming apps. Anne
looked bored and restless. [music] Tyler
looked indifferent, almost lifeless.
"So, what do you want to watch?" Anne
asked. "Good question." "Not sure,"
Tyler responded. "Well, what do you
like?" "H," Tyler mumbled, thinking to
himself for a moment as he continued to
scroll by all his continued watching
list. Stranger Things, Squid Games, The
[music] Office, House of Cards, Friends,
Parks, and Wreck. You know, you should
really go out more, and said suddenly.
You seem like you're always home or
working when you're not with me. It's
not healthy. Yeah, I know. You're right.
[music] Tyler said, "What's the point of
living if you don't enjoy it, right?
Let's go out. Be spontaneous. I want to
check out a new spot I came across the
other day." Okay, sure. The two got up
and left the apartment. They took a ride
share to the address Anne put in.
"Fool's gold." "I think I've been here
before, actually," Tyler said as they
pulled up. "Really?" Anne said,
genuinely surprised. Inside, the two
drank at the bar as lights pulsed around
them and the droning of others voices
amalgamated into a single cacophony.
"Directly next to Tyler, on his left,
sat a woman, possibly in her 40s or 50s.
She was clearly intoxicated and
seemingly by herself. She was drinking
what looked to be a Manhattan while she
watched some kind of travel show on one
of the TV screens behind the bar. I hate
people who travel all the time. She said
loudly to herself with a somewhat raspy,
slurred voice. She leaned over and
looked toward Tyler. You know, "Yeah,
for sure," Tyler said with a forced
laugh. "Why?" [music] Anne interrupted
playfully but earnestly. "Isn't it great
to see the world and different cultures
and people if you can?" For sure that's
true," Tyler said with the corrective
tone. The woman scoffed and turned back
toward the [music] screen. "Just because
you can doesn't mean you should. Most
people do all sorts of things only
because they can, because it looks like
something they should, not because they
actually want or prefer it. I know a lot
of people like that, trust me." The
woman took a sip of her drink while
staying locked onto the show. "Yeah, but
not if you actually like it and choose
the lifestyle for yourself. I know some
people that genuinely like traveling all
the time." Anne said back with
confidence. Some people maybe, but I
find most people don't like half the
they choose to do. Everyone's a
victim to their own bad faith. She
pointed loosely at the screen. Tyler's
head moved back and forth between the
woman and Anne. Yeah, I mean, it's hard
obviously, [music] Anne said. Doing what
you want means inevitably risking
letting other people down, annoying
people, confusing them. It means you'll
feel kind of aimless with no clear
reference points. All the possibilities
of life narrow into the one that's
yours. And it becomes real and entirely
[music] your responsibility. Nothing
scarier than being responsible for your
own life, for how it [music] turns out,
for who you are. But people do make that
choice every day.
The woman grunted [music] as she took a
large swig of her drink. "How about you?
You got any opinion here?" "Uh" she
said, [music] gesturing at Tyler with
two fingers, waving back and forth as if
she was trying to swirl his name out of
the air. Realizing what she wanted, he
looked over at the woman and said,
"Tyler,
Tyler,
what do you think?"
In order to take and maintain better
ownership over our life, [music] we must
first strive to stay true to our
intuitions and curiosities. This
typically involves taking something
internal, our sensibilities, visions, or
ideas, and making it real. Whether that
leads us toward an artistic pursuit, a
business, a social cause, or all [music]
the above, this video sponsor, ODO, is
essential to the next step. A website
gives you the ability to be more in
control [music] of your future. It's a
crucial connection point between what
you do and the entire world. ODU makes
building and managing a website
essentially a plug-and-play process,
both streamlined and creatively [music]
inspiring, and free. Simply fill out a
few prompts, choose the look and
features you want, and then drag and
drop dynamic elements until you have
exactly the website that makes sense for
you [music] and your goals. And again,
with ODU, your first app is free,
including the website builder, along
with unlimited hosting and support, plus
a [music] free custom domain name for
the first year. So, it's a no-brainer to
try. And once you use and love it, they
also offer a full suite of apps for
things like [music] accounting,
inventory management, project goals, and
more, so you can easily organize
everything you do in one [music] place.
Whether you want to create a
professional website to share your story
or brand, or a [music] web store to sell
your products or services, ODU is the
bridge that allows you to take that next
step. Get started on creating what
matters to you for [music] free by using
my link in the description.
And of course, as always, thank you so
much [music] for watching in general and
see you next video.